Dav(id|e|o)? Watson

Software's Liminal Edges: Now is the space between retrospecting the past and prototyping the future

Pittsburgh, PA (412) 614-9301 david@davidwatson.org LinkedIn Github: https://github.com/davidthewatson/

Summary

Won a computer science award before music school. A computer programming internship followed. Devoted twenty years to developing data products, software services, and pipelines of tools. Moved ideas into code, and data into science, from dialog box to documentation.

Experience

2023-2024 Wyvern

Technologist (1099) Nashua, NH

Ally in Software Development LifeCycle (SDLC) around the TypeScript ecosystem from API to HCI, Docker Compose & Kubernetes

2022 Freelance Software Design Engineer Pittsburgh, PA

Prototyped Personal Knowledge Management concept around GPT and Requests, experimented with data in Rust/Polars, and more

Caterpillar

Technical Consultant (1099) Pittsburgh, PA

ZCU-104 PYNQ is rare in that it exposes FPGA without embedded skills. Our port of Intel code gained 20%-50% time optimization using C++ GCC Linux by tweaking FPGA feature flags in GCC without computational complexity analysis or code optimization

Carnegie Mellon University (Emerging Technology Center)

2020

Senior Member of Technical Staff

Pittsburgh, PA

Artificial Intelligence (AI), Human Computer Interaction (HCI), High Performance Computing (HPC)

2018-2020 Caterpillar

Software Engineering Specialist (W-2)

Pittsburgh, PA

- Assembled Sensor Storage for Edge Network on Kubernetes to achieve Dev-Prod Parity using S3 as protocol not product, like Minio
- Collaborated with 12 IT execs on planning and implications of hyperconverged infrastructure on cloud native storage
- Tested web service prototypes related to Git for Data Storage (like Pachyderm or LakeFS) with partner in Golang, optimizing spaced

Rent Jungle (RainMaker (RealPage))

2016-2018

Senior Software Engineer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Led weekly retro resulting in better communication, velocity, and teamwork via nimble methods such as affinity diagrams and pairs
- Crafted Scrapy crawler over Tor (python 3) to cover real estate frontier without detection on Django, PostgreSQL, and Kubernetes

2015-2016 Wellbridge Health

VP Product Development, IT Compliance Officer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Built data analysis and tools from experiments in pandas and Python.
- Deprecated legacy App Store dependency using browser-based Ember SPA MVP designed and delivered in concert with MAYA Design
- Developed API backend on Python 3 Django REST Framework, PostgreSQL emitting JSON API to Ember SPA on Aptible

Hire an Esquire (Major, Lindsey, and Africa)

2014

VP Engineering Pittsburgh, PA

- Led a team of 6 through a lean Python 3 redesign and refactoring of the entire UI/UX from legacy MVP Django system
- Reduced daily production firefighting by using nimble methods, automated tests, CI/CD, code review and design review

Experience (continued)

Forever 2013-2014

Senior Software Developer Pittsburgh, PA

- Prototyped full-stack (Bootstrap to Heroku) cloud idea quickly on Python 3 before porting MVP from Python to Ruby on Rails
- Enabled the company to capture strong market traction in just a year after releasing 1.0 e-commerce platform finished at Neo

SMaSh - Brainstorm SMS Technologies (Mind Matrix)

2011 - 2012

Senior Engineer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Wrote conversational text systems (like twilio) in Python, PostgreSQL, Flask, and Requests
- Supported large SMS text campaigns from Pittsburgh Steelers to Miller-Coors

Wellspring 2010-2011

Software Development Manager

Pittsburgh, PA

- Coded C++ QA tests, maintained Perl code review system, CORVUS FDA-regulated product, team of 12, ~2M SLOC Mac
- Prototyped wireframes and rendered storyboards in C++/PyQt for adaptive 4D treatment planning team of 4

Applied Perception (Foster Miller (Qinetiq))

2008-2009

Project Engineer Pittsburgh, PA

- Visualized XML sonar data in Python <u>Beautiful Soup</u> server and <u>Microsoft Visual C++</u> GUI client application on Windows
- Ported Microsoft C# Windows GUI application to C++, Qt, Ubuntu Linux for OCU deployment

NOMOS (North American Scientific, Best Medical)

2006-2007

UI Software Engineer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Coded C++ QA tests, maintained Perl code review system, CORVUS FDA-regulated product, team of 12, ~2M SLOC Mac
- Prototyped wireframes and rendered storyboards in C++/PyQt for adaptive 4D treatment planning with team of 4

MAYA Design (BCG) 2004-2006

Software Design Engineer Pittsburgh, PA

- Deployed python web services emitting JSON to JDA clients on team of 4 developing A+ Schools, 3RC, DHS to win an award
- Demoed GUI lighting IoT Zigbee PoC in C#.net/COM/Visio on Windows for Phillips execs in 5 days sketch-to-code

Cobind 2003-2004

Cofounder

Pittsburgh, PA

- Stole <u>cobind idea</u> from R&D signifying app/os tightly bound at build-time vs. loosely bound at run-time
- <u>Progeny, Suse</u>, and <u>Timesys</u> built linux online but few if any used browser as UI/UX. Now *spins are in* -common to every distribution.
- Collaborated on Linux Tools startup with cofounder and consultant. Received worldwide press after Idea Foundry Fellowship

Education

<u>Duquesne University</u> BSBA

Coursework Computer Science, Music Education, Technical Writing

Continued Education Git Foundations, PyCon, RDBMS@MIT

Books Crystal Clear, Flow, Lean Software

Interests Reading, Writing, and Running

Passion Fasting Flows into Feasting